Does everyone have everything?
Did you all remember to bring your lunches and water bottles? Snacks?
Yes!
Fujimoto, Kobato, you guys aren't missing anything either, right?
Nope!
You're not bringing anything with you on this trip?
Oh no! Excuse me, I need to get my bag!
Kobato, are you okay?
Yes, I'm all right...
Kobato.
How do I do this again?
The simplest things in life
end up being the most difficult.
I just want to smile when I'm happy
and sing a song whenever I please.
I was told, "Someday, your dream will come true."
But when exactly will that be?
I can't wait that long!
I spread my arms
on the count of one two three
and gather all the light in the world.
Tell me,
isn't there something I can do?
Even if someone hurts my feelings,
I'll keep running toward the light.
Even if I trip, fall, and cry my eyes out, I still believe.
Although it may seem silly...
I believe in tomorrow.
Production
The Kobato Protection Group
...A Little Game of Hide and Seek.
Kobato, there you are.
Ioryogi, let's go!
What?
We're going on a class trip!
I thought it was really lively around here. Is that why?
Yes! It's going to be so much fun!
That's why you need to come too!
I see.
What are you doing? Pick it up!
Right!
Hello, this is Kobato Hanato!
Kobato?
No, I mean, this is Yomogi Nursery!
Who are you?
Someone who's been allowed to work here!
Well aren't you lively.
Thank you.
Is Sayaka there? I'd like to speak to her...
Actually, we're all about to go out on a field trip right now.
Is there something you need?
Yes, there is. Could you pass on a message for me?
Yes!
Tell her to hurry up and stop playing around the nursery.
I won't extend the deadline for her repayment.
Mr. Debt Collector?
Didn't you come to the nursery earlier and bully everyone?
So that's what those guys did...
I'm sorry!
Why are you apologizing?
It seems like I've accused you of something you didn't do...
You're an interesting one.
But unfortunately, you don't have a job anymore.
I'm shutting down the nursery.
No!
Make sure you tell Sayaka now.
Wait, you're--
Shutting down the nursery...
Do you think Miss Sayaka knows the guy who just called?
I'll pass on the trip.
Ioryogi?
Take a nap or something when you get back.
You took forever, jeez.
How long were you gonna keep us waiting?
Now we're behind schedule.
Um, is the debt collector an acquaintance of Miss Sayaka's?
What?
A man called here earlier. He said he was going to shut down the nursery.
Him, huh.
Don't tell Miss Sayaka about the phone call.
But he seemed like a scary person, and...
It's fine, leave it.
Kobato, Fujimoto, we're leaving!
Sorry, we'll be right there.
The entrances are always in the weirdest places.
The Bear's Baumkuchen's Shop
Welcome!
Yo.
Oh it's you.
The name of the store's a little too straight forward, doncha think?
Nothing I can do about it. Both the shop name and the job were already picked out for me.
He even decided that stuff for you?
You're in no place to talk.
You've been given that form and you still haven't learned your lesson?
There's nothing to learn!
I didn't do anything wrong!
You idiot! You caused such a commotion and you're still talking like that?!
If they heard what you said just now, they'd do worse than make you a stuffed animal!
You'll be turned into some tiny one inch tall doll next time.
Whatever, that aside, what'd you come here for?
Stop stalling, just spit it out.
I have something I'd like you to look up for me.
Really now. Let's hear it.
Woah!
So high up!
Look there!
What is it?
It's a pond! A huge pond!
Shut down the nursery.
I wonder who that person on the phone this morning was.
Kobato! Toshihiko, Marina! It's time for lunch!
Okay!
Now I have a boo-boo.
Kobato, you've been getting hurt all morning.
It seems like you've been zoning out all day.
Is there something bothering you?
Umm...
She's always spacing out, isn't she?
Not always!
Don't cause Miss Sayaka unnecessary worry.
Yes...
I want info on Yomogi Nursery and everyone related to it.
Oh?
What? What's with that pathetic look?
Have the investigation skills you were so proud of gone rusty?
And your look is how many times more pathetic than mine?
I can't believe you asked me to do that.
What?
In the past, you'd just command people to get info for you.
And if they didn't listen, you'd start spitting fire and pulling punches.
Then as you wish, an extra large fireball coming right up!
Dammit! Cut that out!
Ah. It's done.
You! You've really gotten used to this job, haven't you?
If your former underlings saw you doing this, they'd cry.
I don't want to hear that from a stuffed animal like yourself.
What'd you say?!
I'll look into that for you.
It's related to that girl, isn't it?
Thanks.
I'll do as you've asked this time.
What do you think you're doing?! Don't eat other people's food!
Kobato?
Yes, Marina?
What's the matter?
Are you worried about something?
Nothing! Nothing at all! Really!
You are.
But it's okay. I'm doing something good right now.
If I can find one, it'll bring good luck.
Kobato! Marina!
Let's play a game!
Okay! I'm coming!
Rock, paper, scissor, shoot!
Once more!
Yay! Kobato's it!
Everyone go hide while Kobato counts to ten!
Try and find us!
All right, I'll do my best!
This is all I get as a souvenir?
If he just piled them up, I could've carried a bunch of these!
This body is so annoying!
And you look pathetic to boot.
I don't wanna hear that from you.
It's been a while, Ginsei.
That really is an embarrassing body.
What was that?!
Even though your appearance is different, you're still the same on the inside, huh.
You can't change back at all?
I have something I need to do.
It's that girl, isn't it?
If you do anything to Kobato, you can kiss your tail goodbye.
Don't forget. I'll definitely be back to settle the score.
Annoying...
I wonder where everyone's hiding...
Not here, hmm...
Where is everybody?
Kobato looks like she's having fun.
She hasn't even found one person yet...
She's looking in a strange place again.
This looks like it's going to take a while.
You guys are so good at hiding!
Hey!
Fujimoto!
It's time to go!
I can't go yet! I'm "it"!
Huh?
The person who's "it" needs to find all the hidden people!
But it's time...
Everybody, it's time to go!
Coming!
There you are!
Kobato... are you ok?
Toshihiko and Yoshio, I found you!
Ah... she did!
She found us!
Yuzuru and Yukari, I see you!
Masao, I've got you too!
There are people hiding over there too!
And over there! And there!
You still have leaves in your hair, Kobato!
I'll get them out for you!
Thank you!
Come, let's get going.
Okay!
Maybe we should take a picture to remember this day by...
Oh no, Marina's not here.
She really isn't here.
I'll go look for her.
Fujimoto!
Miss Sayaka, please stay here with everybody.
I'll go help look too!
Marina!
Did you see her?
No, I didn't.
I wonder if she's still hiding somewhere.
It'd be nice if she really was just playing around...
If only I had found her sooner...
I'll go look over there.
Marina!
Marina?!
She's... asleep.
Thank goodness!
Marina?
Good morning.
Kobato?
I'm sorry... I couldn't find it.
Are you talking about our game of hide-and-seek?
No, the four leaf clover.
If I could find one, it would bring good luck.
I wanted to give it to you.
To me?
Yeah. Because you looked kinda sad today.
I looked everywhere, but I couldn't find one. I'm sorry.
Don't worry about it.
I'm happy.
I'm happy because you tried so hard to cheer me up.
I'm glad!
The view over here is nice. Let's take the picture here.
Everyone, get ready!
Mr. Kiyokazu, hurry!
Don't worry about me, look forward!
What's the matter?
I found one!
A four leaf clover!
Here you go.
Thank you Kobato!
Kobato, look it, look it!
There are so many of them!
We've found lots and lots of good luck, haven't we?
Hey! Let's try taking that picture again!
Okay!
The baumkuchen's all broken.
And after Master Genko went through so much trouble to give you one.
What's going on today?! It's one after another!
You're one of the workers at that bear's place, aren't you?
Your name was...
I forgot.
It's Zuisho! Jeez!
I have a message from Master Genko!
He said he's finished investigating what you asked him about!
What?
That's Genko for you.
Even Nihiru would laugh at you in that form.
What did you say bird brain?!
I'm home!
Huh? Ioryogi hasn't come back yet...
Oh no! Ioryogi's so small, I hope he didn't get stuck somewhere!
Or fall into a crack in the road!
Or get crushed somewhere!
Oh no, this is bad! Ioryogi's in trouble!
Who's in trouble?
Ioryogi!
Yo.
Welcome back!
What's that?
Oh this?
Baumkuchen.
And? How was the field trip?
Oh! I have something for you, Ioryogi!
Here you go!
A good luck clover.
It's a little wilted, but I brought one for you too.
I wish that everyone can stay together in good fortune.
Everyone at Yomogi Nursery.
Reporting!
Apparently the previous head of Yomogi Nursery was tricked and forced to borrow a lot of money.
The previous head?
Sayaka Okiura's father. He passed away two years ago or something like that.
The ones who tricked him were pretty dangerous guys,
and now they're harassing Sayaka Okiura too.
That's a problem now isn't it.
If things keep going like this, sooner or later, Yomogi Nursery is going to get shut down.
Even though we all want to fly,
we're being deceived by gravity.
In reality, everybody can already fly.
The reason why that child looks so sad
might be because she left her shadow somewhere.
If so...
If telling you "Thank you",
or hearing "Thank you" just makes you smile,
then doing those things will make me happy.
And they'll make you happy too.
Don't worry, we're together.
It's mysterious as to why tears roll down
even though I'm happy.
Next
... A Kind Person.